It all started with the birth of a
bioluminescent baby in Qingqing City, China.
That marked the first appearance of
peculiar abilities that would
come to be known as Quirks.
More and more holders of
these abilities were born,
and now the world has become
a super-powered society,
where nearly 80% of the total
population have some kind of Quirk.
A new vocation arose in this
chaotic world: the hero.
Heroes are a select group licensed by
the government to use their powerful
Quirks in service to society.
But this age also has another type of hero.
Nobody chooses them.
These illegal heroes act
on their own initiative.
What is their brand of justice?
Can they even be called
heroes in the first place?
This is the story of vigilantes
trying to become real heroes,
before Izuku Midoriya ever
went to U.A. High School.
vigilante
a member of a volunteer committee organized to suppress
and punish crime summarily (as when the processes of law are viewed
as inadequate); broadly: a self-appointed doer of justice
I'm Here
I... hunger!
A villain's rampaging!
Run for it!
Munch munch!
Teeth are life!
He's got my bike!
Oh man!
It's fine now!
Why?
Because I am here!
Take this, villain!
Detroit Smash!
My teeth!
Wow! All Might!
It was over in one hit!
That's why he's the number one hero!
Is everyone safe and sound?
That's what matters most.
My teeth...
I didn't mean you!
Until next time!
All Might... I just knew seeing
him in person would be awesome!
Whoa, crap!
I'll be late for class!
I-I'm sorry!
Aw, look what you did.
I had just bought that. Now apologize.
Hands and knees.
I-I'm very sorry!
He really did it!
Ain't you got any pride?
What a wuss.
Ow!
You punk.
Screw you!
Asshole!
Get back here!
Koichi Haimawari, a typical college
student who spends all his time at work.
His Quirk is Slide and Glide.
Quirk: Slide and Glide
It lets him move around as if sliding.
Activating it requires at least three
points of contact with a surface.
But it's only as fast...
as a slow bike!
Oh, a mobility-type Quirk?
That could come in handy.
It's not very fast, though.
Looks kind of gross, like a cockroach!
Bug off!
With a pop heart
With a pop beat
Hope my feelings make it to you
With a pop, hip, and hop!
(Self-proclaimed) freelance idol
Pop☆Step
Everyone! Thanks for showing up again today!
I'm always on the prowl
Searching for the smile from that day
With this voice as my guide
I never stop believing
That someday you'll find me
That someday you'll hold me
Shine
Sparkle
P-O-P! S-T-E-P!
Hope it makes it to you
Shine
Sparkle
C'mon, 1-2-3, pop step jump!
A surprise concert by Pop☆Step.
I'll fly away to where you are
Hopefully the police won't notice.
I'll fly away
Her singing's unimpressive,
and you can't tell what she looks
like under the flashy makeup.
But she sparkled like a gem just then,
because she was soaring through the sky.
I wish I had the Leap Quirk.
Shoot, I've got to get to work!
People admire what they
literally look up at.
And when they look down at something,
the opposite tends to happen.
Life.
It sure isn't fair.
You were late,
and I'm deducting it from your pay.
Yes, sir.
I ended up being late anyway.
Welcome.
Damn it, next time I see him...
The cockroach creep.
My Quirk's called Spike.
It's full of stabby pain.
Scared ya, didn't I?!
You loser!
Crap.
What's with those guys?
The cops should do something!
Oh, it ticks me off. Right up to here!
That does it.
Tonight, I'm gonna do it.
Change into my special suit,
and go crazy with my Quirk!
This'll make me feel better!
Who cares about the law!
I'll do everything I can!
Look out, there's my first target!
You dropped this!
The late-night bus stop is over there!
You've got ten minutes until the last train!
Yay!
Oh! Nice Guy's at it again tonight!
Wow, that's so nice. Super nice!
Thank you, Nice Guy.
Great work, Nice Guy.
Put my trash out on your way home!
It feels great when I do so many good deeds!
I am beat. And thirsty.
Here you go.
Hey, thanks.
Wait, who're you?!
Pop☆Step?! What're you doing here?
You always go around town picking
up trash and such, yeah?
Your name's, um...
Cockroach Guy?
Nice Guy!
Is that dweeby hoodie supposed
to be an All Might cosplay?
That's right.
He's my standard for what it means to
be of utmost service to the world.
And it's not dweeby! It's cool!
Utmost, huh?
In your own little way?
Yes, that's right. It's important
to know one's place.
You're Knows-His-Place Guy.
Nice Guy!
Be careful you don't go too far playing
your idol games, or the cops'll catch you.
Oh, and thanks for the drink.
Hey! Who said anything about
games?! I'm for real!
Ow.
Huh?
What's the big idea?
Check out what she's
wearin' under that coat.
What a freak!
I know her. She's famous.
She's a cringy high schooler
who flashes her butt online.
You supposed to be a hero,
in all that makeup?
Or more like a villain?
Stop! Nobody sees my face in public!
E-Excuse me.
Then we'll take pics of
it, and post 'em online!
No!
Dude, you're the worst!
Hey! S-Stop that, you guys.
Huh? What do you care?
Get lost, and take your dumb hoodie with you.
No, it's... not dumb.
Y-You're right, it's none of my business.
Sorry to bother you.
Stop it!
I-It's not a dumb hoodie,
and I'm not "Knows-His-Place Guy."
I'm the dude who can't ignore
someone in trouble: Mr. Nice Guy!
I'm no good at fighting.
Huh? What're you talkin'—
But I can surprise them!
What was that supposed to be?
I didn't recognize you
at first, but I do now.
Nobody asked you to butt in.
The cockroach creep wants to play hero?!
Ouch!
That settles it.
We're not just gonna beat you up.
We're gonna wreck both you and your store!
While we're at it, we'll strip weirdo
chick naked for the world to see!
Wh-Why take it that far?
Because you piss me off so
damn much. Why do you think?!
Stop it! I'll call the police!
Shouldn't you call for a hero instead?
Go on, say, "Help me, All Might!"
Yeah, go on and say it!
All Might's not always available.
C'mon, do it already!
No matter how much we want
him to come save us,
he's not going to drop in out of the—
Wh-What was that?!
Somebody just dropped in?!
Were you guys talking about All Might?
He won't be showing up.
But...
I'm here!
That landing was a little
awkward, but don't sweat it.
A trash pile makes for a
nice cushion in a pinch.
By strengthening my neck further,
I can reduce my risk of
cervical injury and concussion.
What's your deal?
Old ma—
What the hell, man?!
Why'd you do that all of a sudden?!
Who am I, and what am I doing?
I'll answer those questions.
They call me Knuckleduster.
I take out the trash—scumbags like you!
Janitor of the Fist
Knuckleduster
Is this guy insane?!
No discoloration.
He's not one.
Next...
He's not one either.
Hey, kid!
I-I'm not involved with these guys...
You've got promise.
I could use some help with my work.
I'm gonna turn you into a hero.
No thanks!
Uh, I'm not interested in that sorta thing.
I-I'm leaving.
That's a lie.
You revere All Might,
and you're into helping people.
Yet you say you're not interested
in doing hero work?
Yeah, but I could never get a
license with my measly Quirk.
So what?
"So what"?
Powerful Quirks and pro licenses?
Those things have nothing at
all to do with true justice!
When you're faced with something you
must do, can you take action or not?!
That's the only question the
hero's spirit has to answer!
In other words, this guy's unlicensed?!
Enough of your justice BS, you old fart!
Stand down. Taking a hostage won't
make me hit you any softer.
She's no hostage!
I'm gonna use Spike to mess up her face!
Nothin' else is gonna satisfy me!
No!
Let me go!
When you're faced with
something you must do...
Stop it!
can you take action or not?!
That's the only question the
hero's spirit has to answer!
Well done, kid!
Wrong on all three counts.
But I'll check their IDs, just to be safe.
Kid, I'll teach you all about
how satisfying hero work is.
Nothing feels better than
pounding on villains.
Th-That's absolutely a "no" for me.
What went through my head then
wasn't "thanks" or "you saved me."
It was, "This guy's even more dangerous."
So, about that dangerous guy.
Student ID
Registration number:
Sociology Department
DOB: February 22, XXXX
Date of enrollment: X X, XXXX
Full name: Koichi Haimawari
Hitonami University President
Koichi Haimawari, age 19.
Freshman at Hitonami University.
Hey, that's my student ID! And my wallet!
I'll call you "Koichi."
Or would you prefer "Nice Guy"?
Please don't rifle through my stuff!
You can call me "master."
I told you, I'm not going
to be your apprentice.
And this is my place, so I wish you'd leave.
What, all you've got in
the fridge is barley tea?
Ah, you do have beer.
Those are for when upperclassmen
from my school come by!
You're too young to have this stuff.
It's confiscated.
He's not listening to a word I say!
Ow...
Those pieces of shit.
I swear I'll kill both the cockroach
creep and the old thug.
No, we should keep away from that guy.
My, my.
You guys got roughed up bad.
Huh? Who're you?
I've got just the medicine you need.
I'm on the hunt for a drug that's
making the rounds in this city.
A drug?
Yeah. It's new and dangerous.
They call it Trigger.
It weakens the user's ability to reason
and boosts their Quirk.
In other words, it turns
ordinary people into villains.
This is wild!
At this rate, villains'll be
popping up all over the place.
Can't ignore that!
But shouldn't we leave that
stuff to heroes and the police?
Can't count on them.
Trigger-induced pop-up villains
suddenly emerge from the crowd.
The police and pro heroes will
always be a step behind.
That's where we come in.
Did you just say "we"?
That's right!
You and I'll stop anyone suspicious,
and check their tongues.
Tongues?
A Trigger addict's tongue changes
color as a side effect.
It turns dark.
Oh. So, that's why you were
looking at their tongues.
That's right!
I'll beat up anyone with a
black tongue on the spot,
question them about who their dealer is,
and smash this drug trade at the source!
You just up and start hitting them?
You gotta make the first move!
Hit the junkies before they
take their Trigger hit!
I doubt they'll cooperate when
you say, "Show me your tongue."
Anyone that suspicious gets a beatdown too!
You are kidding, right?
Or so I hoped, but you weren't kidding!
What's all the fuss?
Oh, Pop☆Step!
Well, you see, we're...
So, you're looking for junkies and dealers.
Thanks for yesterday, pal.
But I haven't forgotten the way you
tried to leave me high and dry.
You do you.
So, Nice Guy.
You can call me "Koichi."
Is that your real name?
Okay, Koichi. Why're you
helping him with this stuff?
What was that pause for?
Oh, well, I mean, if I don't watch this guy,
he's liable to punch every
single person who walks past.
I'm making sure to hit the
suspicious ones first.
All those flighty youngsters, for starters.
That approach is way too random.
Why don't you two use your heads some more?
Someone's definitely taken pictures
of villains who've popped up in town,
so first narrow down your
locations by searching for
"villain I've never seen" or
"villain from out of nowhere."
Then you can start questioning people.
Hey, that's clever.
Hey!
You there!
Not again!
Stick out your tongue!
Whoa, whoa!
This guy just looks like
an ordinary office worker!
Stick out your tongue!
Oh, I'm sorry!
Are those action figures, like for kids?
A grown-ass adult walking around with dolls?
That's suspicious.
There are lots of people
into that sort of thing!
Um, I work in the toy business.
See? He's just trying to do his job.
That's what I'm about to check.
First, I make him do as I say.
Acts of violence in broad daylight.
Not very sensible.
Are you one of those instant villains
who are so common these days?
You must be...
the Erasure Hero: Eraser Head!
Hi, Koichi Haimawari here.
I've started doing hero work, despite my lack of a license.
My hero name is The Crawler!
I get involved in a major incident!
Next time, "Takeoff"!
I want to fly, too!